https://www.campbell.edu/policies/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Privacy Statement
Campbell University is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you a safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to data collection and usage on the Campbell University website. By using the Campbell University website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. However, at any time you may withdraw your consent in connection with any data collection for purposes of deleting Personal Data that is no longer necessary in relation to the purpose for which it was collected.
For purposes of this Privacy Statement, Personal Data shall mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.
Collection of your Personal Information
Campbell University collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address, telephone number, credit card/debit card information, etc. through forms that you complete. Such forms include, but are not limited to, contact forms, applications, information requests and online payments. Campbell University also collects anonymous demographic information that is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age and gender.
There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Campbell University. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. This information is used by Campbell University for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Campbell University website.
Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Campbell University blog/news comments, this information may be collected and used by others. Campbell University does not read any of your private online communications.
Campbell University encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Campbell University so that you can understand how those websites collect, use, and share your information. Campbell University is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Campbell University family of websites.
Campbell University collects and uses your personal information to operate the Campbell University website and deliver the services you have requested. Campbell University also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other academic services or offerings available at Campbell University. Campbell University may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current academic services or programs that may be offered.
Campbell University does not sell, rent, or lease its contact lists to third parties. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Campbell University may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, or provide customer support. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Campbell University, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.
Campbell University does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.
Campbell University keeps track of the websites and pages our visitors view in order to determine what content is the most popular. This data is used to deliver improved and customized content and advertising within Campbell University to visitors whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.
Campbell University websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Campbell University or the website; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Campbell University; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Campbell University or the public.
Opt Out of Personal Data Collection & Use
If you want to opt out of the collection and/or use of Personal Data, please email privacy@campbell.edu.
FERPA
Pursuant to the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) the following information is considered directory information and available to the public unless a restriction from publication of information form is filed with the Campbell University Office of the Registrar by September 1 of the current school year.:
Student name
Dates of attendance
Degree(s) received
Academic majors and minors
Current student local address
Telephone numbers
Religious denomination
Academic classification (freshman, sophomore, etc.)
Academic Dean’s and President’s Lists
Membership in academic honor or service organizations
Elected member of the Student Government Association
Last institution attended
Most recent institution attended
Participation in officially recognized activities and sports
Weight and height of members of athletic teams
Learn more about FERPA
Use of Cookies
The Campbell University website uses “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.
One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you register with Campbell University site or services like access to the library databases or registering for parking online, a cookie helps Campbell University to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as mailing address or email address.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer.
If you have questions about our cookie policy, please contact Campbell University at webfeedback@campbell.edu.
Opt Out of Cookie Collection
Google Analytics Advertising Features
If you wish to opt out of our Google Analytics Advertising Features, you may do so by using Google’s Opt-out Browser Add-on.
Hotjar
If you wish to opt out of our Hotjar activity visualization tool, you may do so by using Hotjar’s Opt-out Feature.
Security of your Personal Information
Campbell University secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Campbell University secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.
Changes to this Statement
Campbell University will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect feedback. Campbell University encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Campbell University is protecting your information.
Contact Information
Campbell University welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Campbell University has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Campbell University at privacy@campbell.edu.
Disclaimer
Where the policy stated herein is in conflict with any federal, state, or foreign law regarding the protection of data as described herein then the federal, state, or foreign law shall prevail.
Sidebar
Policies & Procedures
Anonymous and Obscene Telephone Calls
Privacy Policy
Title IX at Campbell University
Tobacco Policy
Weapons & Explosives
Withdrawal Policies
Campbell University sites use cookies. By continuing to use this site you accept our privacy and cookie policy. View our policyAccept
